# Tim Lewis Cell: 720-418-0533

Email: timothydlewis@icloud.com

**LinkedIn:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/gunfightingyeti **Website:** https://gunfightingyeti.github.io/Assignment3/Bootstrap%20Website/index.html

**Github:** https://github.com/GunFightingYeti

# PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

## HARD WORKING - DEDICATED - QUICK LEARNER - PROBLEM SOLVING

Extremely hard working. Cares greatly about impacting the surrounding community for the better. Values honesty and integrity as core principles in work and life. Strives to produce high quality results. Skill sets in varying backgrounds contributes to the ability to adapt quickly. Experience in managing other employees and large groups of individuals. No challenge is too small, and no puzzle is unsolvable.

- Personal Safety Multiple 2<sup>nd</sup> Dan Black Belts
- Leadership
- Public Speaking
- Organization and Planning
- Critical Thinking

- Customer service
- Technical Support
- Personal Fitness
- Maintenance
- Cleaning

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Spectrum Retirement Director of Maintenance Centennial, Colorado December 2016 – Present

As Director of Maintenance my job is to make sure the community runs smoothly. I am responsible for every part of the building both inside and out. My daily tasks include: Work order completion/resident requests, apartment make readies, preventative maintenance, systems upkeep, cleanliness, atmosphere of the building and vendor relations. I aim to make the community look and run like a high-end hotel but feel like a home.

### Responsibilities as Director of Maintenance:

- Work Orders My goal is to address work orders the day they are received so residents feel that their request is answered promptly, respectfully and cheerfully.
- Apartment Make Readies Patch and paint walls, shampoo carpet, cleaning, general fixes.
- PM Maintain vendor contracts for elevators, RTUs, pest control, fire systems, grounds, security systems. Maintain exit signs, PTAC/VTAC filters, fire extinguishers, life safety drills.
- Systems Upkeep Maintaining water softeners, boilers, fire suppression and supply orders.
- Cleanliness Over-seeing the Housekeeping department to keep a healthy living environment.
- Atmosphere This is by far the most difficult to achieve. I have found that most of the look and feel of a building depends on the attitude of staff and management. I choose to lead by example, keeping my attitude positive and being willing to step in whenever necessary to get results.
- Vendor Relations Maintaining positive working relationships with various vendors and overseeing projects as needed.

MorningStar Senior Living at Dayton Place Maintenance Assistant

Denver, Colorado June 2016 – December 2016

As a Maintenance Assistant my job was primarily completing work orders, preventative maintenance and completing room turns.

### Responsibilities as Maintenance Assistant:

- Work Orders Running toilets, squeaky doors, faucet and shower repair, light bulb replacement, etc.
- Regular and preventative maintenance Filter changes, winterization, general grounds upkeep, pool
  maintenance and recording past and potential problems with the purpose of maintaining high
  efficiency in the future.
- Large Projects Major overhauls of existing systems or replacing systems entirely.
- Cleaning Everywhere I went I looked at the community through the eyes of an owner to make sure I
  was happy with the level of cleanliness.
- Apartment turn over Make an apartment ready for the next resident by painting, patching walls, cleaning carpets and ensuring all items worked correctly.

## Premier Martial Arts & CrossFit Southlands Head Instructor – Manager – Marketing – Maintenance

Aurora, Colorado October 2011 – June 2016

My primary job at Premier Martial Arts was Head Instructor, which consisted of teaching classes and running events and seminars. Within my work as Head Instructor I was also responsible for managing other employees, marketing, customer service, technical support, maintenance, and cleaning.

### Responsibilities as Head Instructor:

- Teach all ages from 3 years old to adult
- Instruct Krav Maga (Israeli self-defense), American Kickboxing, Tae Kwon Do and Muay Thai
- Level 2 Krav Maga certification and Instructor certifications through Premier Martial Arts International
- Teach seminars in Kids Safety, Bully Proof, Adult/Women's Self Defense, Gun/Knife defense, Mass Casualty Event Training
- Run special events- Martial Art Birthday Parties, School Presentations, Assemblies, Fundraisers

# Responsibilities as Manager:

- In charge of all part time instructors, front desk staff, and new hire training
- Coordinate part time instructor schedules for classes, special events, extra coverage
- Assign tasks and projects to other staff members and follow up on their work
- Stocking and replacing basic items: toilet paper, paper towels, light bulbs, cleaning and other supplies.

#### Responsibilities in Marketing:

- Market for the sale of martial arts lessons, special events and promotional booths
- Promote events with business partnerships
- Built rapport with approximately 30 businesses through promotional stands and maintained detailed records
- Organize self-defense seminars for other business' staff and employees

## **Responsibilities in Customer Service:**

- Communicate with students and parents to maintain large student base
- Create and maintain announcements: verbal, e-mail, written and social media

 Shared responsibility for front lobby, answer incoming calls and walk-ins, prep new students, the sale of merchandise and FAQ

### **Responsibilities as Technical Support:**

- Create training documents
- Compose templates for automated e-mails
- Troubleshoot computer issues and service printers at a basic level
- Coordinate all music played in the building and maintained accounts - Spotify, Pandora, iTunes.
- Create stations and playlist that were acceptable for all ages
- · Basic spelling and grammar checks
- Run social media, add new content, manage inquiries and keep up to date

### Responsibilities in Maintenance:

- Fix, tighten, oil and even replace hinges on residential and commercial doors
- Install new hardware: shelves, file holders, workout equipment, wall decorations
- Replace standard and florescent bulbs, fix bathroom stall doors and replace bathroom dividers, paint, TV mounting and hanging, replace ceiling tiles, run speaker wire and install speakers, window decal removal and installation, repair leaks in commercial roof, change HVAC filters, hang marketing signs, open signs, interior/exterior banners, inspirational posters

## Responsibilities in Cleaning:

 Bathrooms, toilets, sinks, urinals, windows (towel and squeegee), pick up trash in and around the building, empty trash cans, clean up bodily fluids, sweep and mop multiple floor types, tidy work spaces Twin Eagle Consulting is a group of consulting engineers with a focus on radio installation and monitoring. As a NOC Technician I was in charge of creating technical walk-through, installation and radio layout documentation. I monitored radio networks for Police, Firefighters, Water and Oil Companies. Responsibilities included setting up notifications in the event that all or part of a client's radio network system went down, then contacting the appropriate crew to fix the issue. I oversaw construction of radio towers in oil fields and upon completion, setup and installed radio monitoring equipment. I also assisted in helping construct and implement Twin Eagle's Network Operations Center.

Van D's HVAC HVAC Technician Denver, Colorado May 2007 – January 2009

Van D's is a small company specializing in Heating, Ventilating and Air Conditioning. I installed HVAC units, water heaters, minor plumbing, electrical and swamp coolers. These tasks required a great deal of physical labor and at times difficult working conditions in attics and crawl spaces. During this time, I also installed a deck for my house and a roof extension on the company owners barn.

#### **EDUCATION**

Graduated - High Peaks Academy DU'S Full Stack Developer Bootcamp

### **HOBBIES AND INTERESTS**

Martial Arts (Krav Maga), Parkour/Free Running, Camping and Backpacking, Snowboarding, Science, physics, Cooking, Gaming, Playing Music (Guitar, Piano, Drums, Cello, Bass), Movies, Solving Puzzles, Time with Friends

References available upon request